Shoma and Kanba - Inside the Box - 10 years ago - We've met. But we didn't have much time left. Hunger and thirst struck.
ここに来てから何日が過ぎただろう
How many days have passed since I got here?
もうずいぶん長い間何も食べてない
I haven't eaten anything for a long time.
このまま僕は死ぬのかな
Am I just going to die like this?
Why...?
どうして
おい　晶馬　生きてるか
Hey, Shoma.
Are you alive?
生きてるよ　冠葉は
I'm alive.
What about you, Kanba?
なんとかな
Just barely.
目が回る
I'm getting woozy.
さっき夢を見たよ　大盛りのカレーを食ってたんだ
I just had a dream.
I was eating an extra large curry rice.
That sounds nice.
いいな
そっか　夢で食べればいいのか
I guess I can just eat in my dreams.
You'd better not.
やめとけ
目が覚めたら　余計腹が減ってる　最悪だ
You'll just be hungrier when you wake up.
It sucks.
それに
Also...
なに
What?
寝ない方がいい
I don't think you should sleep.
今度眠ったら　もう目覚めないような気がする
If you do...
I don't think you'll ever wake up again.
You mean, I'll die?
それ　死ぬってこと
あー　このままだとな
Yeah.
At this rate...
冠葉
Kanba!
来たか　晶馬
So, you've come.
You're finally here, Shoma.
決着をつけよう　冠葉
Let's settle this once and for all.
Kanba!
ひまりはどこだ　ひまりを返せ
Where's Himari?
Give her back to me!
ひまりなら　ここにいる
She's right here.
Himari!
ひまり
It's not too late yet.
まだ間に合う
Completing this mission is the only way to save Himari.
これを成功させることだけがひまりの命を救う唯一の方法
The Survival Strategy.
生存戦略なんだ
The Survival Strategy?
生存戦略
真に純粋な生命の世界は利己的なルールが支配している
A genuine ecosystem
is ruled by self-serving rules.
そこに人の善悪は関与できない
The values of right and wrong are irrelevant.
つまり　もう何者もこの運命を止められないのさ
In other words, no one can stop this fate.
Momoka.
桃果ちゃん　見せてあげるよ
I'll show you
世界が壊れるところを
the destruction of the world.
あれからまた何日経ったんだろう
How many days have passed since?
だんだん体の感覚もなくなってきた
My body is starting to go numb.
晶馬　まだ生きてるか
Shoma.
Are you still alive?
うん　冠葉もまだ生きてるんだね
Yes.
You're alive, too.
Hey, wanna make a promise?
な　約束しないか
約束
A promise?
Sooner or later, one of us will die.
このままじゃいずれどちらかが死ぬ
その前に約束しておくんだ
We'll make a promise before that happens.
何を
Promise what?
Whoever gets out of here alive will do something in the other's stead.
もしどちらかが生きてここを出られたら
そいつがもう一人の代わりにしたいことをする
俺は大切な人に伝えてほしい言葉がある
I have a message for someone precious to me.
Then, I'll send a message to someone precious to me too.
なら　僕もそうしようかな
大切な人に伝えてほしい言葉か
誰だろう
I wonder who...
誰に何を伝えればいいんだろう
What will my message be?
あれ　なんだ
Huh? What's this?
どうした
What is it?
I see something.
何かある
I see something in the corner of my box.
俺の箱の隅っこに何かある
どうしてなんだよ　冠葉
Why, Kanba?
People need light.
人はね　光が必要なんだ
そして彼は漸く見つけた
And he has finally found his own.
光を　希望を
His own light.
His own hope.
それだけが彼の生きる意味なんだ
That is the meaning of his life.
なのに今　世界は彼から光を奪おうとしている
But now, the world is trying to steal his light.
君も世界に加担して　彼を闇の中に置き去りにしているんだよ
You're siding with the world
and trying to leave him behind in the darkness.
そんな
No...
僕だけが　彼を救ってあげられるんだ
Only I can save him.
光に届く力を彼に与えられる
I can give him the power to reach the light.
君は彼に何を与えられるの
What can you give him?
僕が冠葉に与えられるもの
What I can... give him?
荻野目さん
Oginome!
How did you get here?
どうしてここに
運命の乗り換えに来たのよ
I've come to transfer fate.
日記に呪文を使って　ひまりちゃんを救うの
I'll use the spell in the diary to save Himari!
頑張るね
You don't give up, do you?
But how will you do that?
でも　どうする
日記は燃やしちゃったよ
We already burned the diary.
君は呪文を知らないよね
You don't know the spell, do you?
The most important phrase Momoka left behind.
桃果ちゃんが残した一番大切な言葉を
It's our new song.
新曲なんです　ひまりちゃんに聞いてもらいたくて
We want Himari to hear it.
その歌はひまりちゃんが一番大切にしていた言葉を
It's titled after the phrase Himari cherished the most.
タイトルにしたんです
言葉なら　分かる
I know the phrase.
You gotta be shittin' me.
マジで
I know the most cherished phrase.
一番大切な言葉なら　知ってるわ
I will bet everything on that phrase.
あたしはそれに賭ける
でもいいの
Are you sure?
呪文を使うと君が代償を払うんだ
If you use the spell, you'll end up paying the price.
The cursed fire will burn you away from the world's scenery.
呪いの炎に焼かれて　世界の風景から消えちゃうよ
I'll take the punishment!
罰なら受ける
それでも　あたしは大切な人を救いたいの
I want to save the people I love no matter what.
Don't, Oginome.
やめろ　荻野目さん
I've already made up my mind.
あたし　決めたから
そうか
I see.
This was our fate.
これが僕たちの運命だったんだ
君も僕たち兄弟の過去に呪われてるんだ
You, and me and my brother were all cursed in the past.
そうだろう　冠葉
Isn't that right, Kanba?
リンゴだ　リンゴがあった
It's an apple.
I found an apple!
Look around.
探してみろ　お前のところにもあるはずだ
There must be one in your box, too.
ないよ　冠葉は選ばれたんだ
There isn't.
You've been chosen, Kanba.
選ばれた
Chosen... by whom?
誰に　何に
By what?
これで決まり　生き残るのは冠葉だ
It's decided.
You're the one who survives.
冠葉　守ってくれるよね
You'll keep the promise, right?
大切な人への伝言
You'll send the message to my precious someone, right?
分かった
Yes.
悪いな　これが運命なんだ
I'm sorry.
This is fate.
やっと分かったよ
I finally understand
あの時僕たちが出会った理由が
the reason we met back then.
この時のためだったんだ
It was all for this very moment.
生存戦略
Survival Strategy!
Kan.
冠ちゃん　目を覚まして
Wake up.
Himari, is that you?
ひまり　ひまりなのか
Yes.
うん　冠ちゃんを迎えに来たよ
I've come to bring you back.
Let's go home.
一緒に帰ろう
Go home?
帰る
Not yet.
まだ駄目だ　俺はお前にまだなにも
I still haven't...
As it turns out, living was a punishment.
ね　生きるってことは罰なんだね
I've been punished in small doses living as a Takakura.
私　高倉家で暮らしている間
ずっと小さな罰ばかり受けてたよ
I see.
そうか　僕らは始まりからすべて罰だったんだ
Everything was a punishment from the get go.
Sho, you were always like a bickering mother to us, even when you were little.
晶ちゃんは子供の頃から口うるさいお母さんみたい
Telling us to arrange our shoes;
脱いだ靴は揃えるとか
not to swear
汚い言葉は使うなとか
or eat until everyone's home.
夕飯は家族揃ってからとか
Kan, you always try to take a nap after meal.
冠ちゃんは食事の後すぐ寝転がるよね
You never listened when I said you'll turn into a cow.
牛になるよって言っても聞かないし
And please stop leaving used kleenex around after blowing your nose.
あと　鼻をかんだティッシュを放りっぱなしにするのはやめて
That's why we always said you had yucky playboy Kanba-germs.
そんなんだから　女にだらしないバッチイ冠葉菌って言われちゃうんだよ
One day, my parents suddenly told me to call him my "older brother."
あの日　突然父さんと母さんがあいつのことを兄と呼べって言ってさ
I didn't need an older brother.
僕が兄貴なんて要らなかったんだ
Why does he get to be the older brother in the first place?
大体　なんで冠葉が兄貴なんだよ
How can we suddenly become brothers?
そんないきなり兄弟なんかになれるかよ
But, still, we were together.
でも　それでも　私たちは一緒にいたよ
We took all the punishments, no matter how small and trivial.
どんな小さくてつまらない罰もね
They're all precious memories.
大切な思い出
Because the only reason I felt alive was because you two were there.
だって　私が生きてるって感じられたのは
冠ちゃんと晶ちゃんがいたから
Because I was able to be Himari Takakura.
高倉ひまりでいられたから
I don't want to forget everything,
私　忘れたくないよ　失いたくないよ
lose everything.
Please, come back to me.
お願い　帰ってきて
Kan.
冠ちゃん
No, I...
駄目だ　俺は
I still... haven't given you a thing yet.
俺は　まだお前に何も与えていない
家の壁にペンキを塗ろうって言ったのは冠葉だった
Kanba was the one who thought of painting the house.
I was against it.
僕は反対したよ　これ以上目立ってどうするんだって
Why do we want to stand out even more?
そしたら　言ったよな　　(大丈夫)
Then you told me:
It's okay.
ひまりが笑顔で帰って来られるのはうちなんだ
Our house should be a place Himari can come home to with a smile.
大丈夫だよ
And that you'd do anything to make that happen.
そのためにはなんでもするって
It was raining on that day.
あの日は　雨が降ってたな
We found the bed by the dumpster.
ひまりのベット　近所のゴミ捨て場で見つけたんだ
The two of us carried the legs and got home all soaked.
晶馬と二人　柱を抱えて
びしょ濡れになりながら家に帰った
Kan...
Kan?
冠ちゃん
Kan.
冠ちゃん　ほら
It's okay.
大丈夫だよ　痛くないでしょう
It doesn't hurt, right?
Himari.
ひまり
It was fun.
楽しかった　ありがとう
Thank you.
返すよ　あの日兄貴が僕に分け与えた物
I'll return what you shared with me on that day.
The life you gave me.
僕にくれた命
Our love and our punishment, too.
僕たちの愛も　僕たちの罰も
We'll share it all.
皆分け合うんだ
It was our beginning.
これが　僕たちの始まり　運命だったんだ
It was our fate!
Kan.
冠ちゃん　これがピングドラムだよ
This is the Penguindrum.
Kan...ba?
冠　葉
Let's share the fruit of fate.
運命の果実を一緒に食べよう
Let's share the fruit of fate!
荻野目さん
Oginome!
The fate transfer is about to commence.
ただいまより　運命の乗り換えが始まります
Please do not miss the transfer if you wish to come aboard.
乗り換えをご希望のお客様はお乗り遅れのないよう　お急ぎください
ただいまより　運命の乗り換えが始まります
None of you will ever escape the curse.
君たちは決して呪いから出ることはできない
As I could not,
僕がそうであるように
residents of the boxes like you could never gain anything.
箱の中の君たちが何かを得ることなどない
You will all simply disappear without leaving anything behind in this world.
この世界に何も残さず　ただ消えるんだ
You won't even leave a fleck of dust behind.
塵一つ残せないのさ
You will never be happy!
君たちは絶対に幸せになんかなれない
Shoma.
晶馬　俺は手に入れたよ
I have obtained...
true light!
本当の光を
This is our punishment.
これは僕たちの罰だから
What?
Thank you.
ありがとう　愛してる
I love you.
The train has left.
列車はもう行っちゃったわ
You're not going anywhere.
あなたはどこにも行けないの
The train will come again.
列車はまた来るさ
I don't know about that, but I'm leaving.
さあ　でも私はもう行くわ
I see.
そう
Good bye.
さよなら
何が起きたの　君たち大丈夫か
Are you two okay?
Welcome Back!
What happened?
何があったの
Any doctors here?
誰か医者はいるのか
Yuri.
ゆり　やっと分かったよ
I finally understand...
why we were left behind in this world.
どうして　僕たちがこの世界に残されたのかが
教えて
Tell me.
You and I were lost children to begin with.
君と僕は予め失われた子供だった
But most children in the world are same as us.
でも世界中のほとんどの子供たちは僕らと一緒だよ
So, just once,
だから　たった一度でもいい
we needed someone to say "I love you."
誰かの愛してるって言葉が必要だった
Even if fate steals everything from them, the loved children will definitely find happiness.
たとえ運命がすべてを奪ったとしても
愛された子供はきっと幸せを見つけられる
We were left behind in this world to do just that.
私たちはそれをするために　世界に残されたのね
I love you.
愛してるよ
愛してるわ
Sister?
お姉さま
Mario?
マリオさん　もう大丈夫なの
Are you cured?
Huh?
Oh, never mind.
いいえ　気のせいね
It was all just a dream.
あんな夢を見たから
A dream?
夢
え　とても不思議な夢
Yes.
A very strange dream.
I had another brother in the dream.
わたくしにお兄様がいたのよ
お兄様
Another brother?
A twin brother.
わたくしの二子のお兄様
Was he like you?
お姉様に似てらした
Not at all.
いいえ　ちっとも
He was a very heavy-handed person.
とても不器用な人だったわ
But he said I was a precious sister.
だけど　わたくしのことを大切な妹だと
That he loved me.
愛してると言っていたわ
あ　おじさん　今日遅くなるの
Oh, Uncle?
You'll be late tonight?
おばさんも
Auntie too?
うん　夜食はあるよ
Okay.
You'll have dinner.
I'm making curry rice now.
今カレー作ってるから
Don't worry, I'm not lonely at all.
大丈夫だよ　寂しくないから
A friend of mine is visiting for lunch.
お昼はお友達がくるんだ
Yes.
うん　ほら　この前一緒に水族館に行った
You know, the one I went to the aquarium with...
Yes.
そう　あの時病院で知り合った
The one I met in the hospital.
Yes.
うん　すっごく気が合うんだ
We get along really well.
Age 6
Age 7
Her presence relaxes me, and...
二人でいると　なんだか落ち着くし
なんだろうね
うん　そうだね　(いただきます)
Let's eat!
I don't know... I guess...
同じ電車で二人同時に倒れるなんて
It's a rare coincidence for the two of us to pass out on the same train.
It's so good!
めったに偶然だもんね
美味しい　ひまりちゃんまた腕上げたね
You've gotten better again, Himari!
It's all thanks to the recipe you gave me.
リンゴちゃんが教えてくれたレシピのおかげだよ
It's my family's secret apple recipe.
我が家の秘伝のリンゴだね
あ　ダブルエッチ
Oh, it's Double-H!
They're so cute.
超可愛いよね　私　グッズ集めてるんだ
I'm collecting their merchandise.
Me too!
あたしも　これ新曲だよね
This is their new song, right?
うん　アルバム買ったよ　聞く
Yes.
I bought the album.
Wanna listen?
Yeah, let's!
聞く聞く
Hang on a sec.
ちょっと待ててね
Let's see, where did I leave the newest one?
ええと　一番新しいのは　どこに置いたっけ
あっあれ　縫いぐるみ
Huh? A teddy bear?
何かな
What's this?
We love you!! From your brothers
Brothers?
お兄ちゃん　誰
Whose...?
Himari?
ひまりちゃん
It's strange...
あれ　変だな
どうして私泣いてるの
Why am I crying?
Simply put, the apple is also a reward for those chosen to die for love!
つまり　リンゴは愛による死を自ら選択した者へのご褒美でもあるんだよ
But everything's over when you're dead.
でも　死んだら　全部お終いじゃん
お終いじゃないよ
It's not over!
What Kenji was trying to say is that's
actually where everything begins!
むしろそこから始まるって　賢治は言いたいんだ
Chestnuts
I love the word "fate."
私は運命って言葉が好き
I believe that I'm never alone.
信じてるよ　いつだって一人なんかじゃない
Hey, where are we going?
ね　僕たちどこ行く
Where do you want to go?
どこへ行きたい
Let's see.
そうだな　じゃ
How about...
本字幕由诸神字幕组（kamigami.org）制作，仅供交流学习，禁止用于任何商业用途
日听：hunter 翻译:ASUKA 校对:冷漠的风  木落 时间轴:wcaster 压制:wcaster
I will never forget you.
忘れないよ絶対に
ずっと　ずっと
Forever and ever.
I Love You